appcues.com 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

‍

Appcues is committed to protecting the privacy of all its users.

In order to ensure that our customers and users are fully informed of our data handling policies and their rights pertaining to this data, we maintain this page which details our practices around information collected through the Appcues platform.

 **Last updated:** 2018-02-01

### Overview

‍

Our approach to data security and privacy includes but is not limited to:

  * State-of-the-art platform security
  * At-rest and in-transit encryption of all customer and end-user data
  * Providing customers with the tools to control the amount of personally-identifiable information (PII) handled by Appcues
  * Compliance with the [European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://eugdpr.org/) and the [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) program

### Kinds of Information We Collect

‍

Appcues processes four different categories of data, which reflect the different levels of sensitivity in context. However, there are several common traits about how we handle the data, regardless of type:

  *  **We never sell this data to third parties.** In limited cases, we provide it to third-party services for usage strictly within the Appcues product or business; for example, to provide analytics graphs on the Appcues dashboard.
  *  **All data is subject to the protections of the General Data Protection Regulation** , in the case it originates from the European Union.

‍

#### Type 1: End-user PII  

This is the most sensitive type of data that Appcues collects. Examples:

  * Any user profile data passed to Appcues by the customer, using the `Appcues.identify()` SDK function
  * Browser information that is collected by default in the Appcues SDK (e.g., OS, device type, browser language, user agent)
  * Browsing history data that is collected by default in the Appcues SDK (e.g., current page URL, current page title)

We reiterate that like all data we collect, **end-user PII is never sold to third parties.**

Customers may opt out of browser and browser history information by contacting [Appcues Support](mailto:support@appcues.com).

This data is used in the targeting and customization of Appcues content.

‍

#### Type 2: End-user Appcues Data

This data pertains to how end users are interacting with Appcues content; for example, whether a flow was shown to a given user, whether a user has clicked away a tooltip, etc. This category also includes user responses to in-Appcues forms or surveys.

Though this category usually does not contain PII, **we caution that form or survey responses may add PII to this data**.

End-user Appcues data is provided to service providers for usage within the Appcues platform. Customers may also configure Appcues to send this data upstream to other services via [Segment](https://segment.com/).

Data in this category is used in the targeting and customization of Appcues content, as well as displaying analytics on the Appcues dashboard.

It is this data stream which is available for CSV download on the Appcues dashboard.

‍

#### Type 3: Customer PII

Customer PII is collected by the Appcues dashboard, for example the name and email address of each of a customer's team members who are authorized to use the Appcues platform.

Appcues does not store financial data about customers (e.g., credit card information), choosing instead to employ a dedicated payments processor.

Data of this type is used mainly in the Appcues dashboard and editor, and within the Appcues business.

‍

#### Type 4: Customer Aggregate Data

This category includes customer-wide statistics such as active user count, number of Appcues flows shown, how many Appcues flows are published at a time, etc.

This data does not contain PII.

Data in this category is used mainly in the Appcues dashboard and editor, customer emails, and within the Appcues business.

‍

### Security and Compliance

‍

#### GDPR

The [European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://eugdpr.org/) is a law that regulates the transfer of personal data out of the European Union, that takes effect May 2018. The GDPR enumerates the rights of end users with regards to data collected about them, including the right to view, delete, and/or cease collecting this data.

Compliance with the GDPR is a practical requirement of any data service like Appcues with end users in the European Union. Further, it is the moral duty of data processors to protect the privacy rights of their users.

 **Appcues is fully and proudly compliant with the GDPR.**

More information is available in our Legal section below.

‍

#### PCI Data Security Standard

Appcues is fully compliant with the [PCI Data Security Standard](https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/), which regulates the handling and retention of payment data. Appcues does not handle customer payment data directly, instead using a fully PCI DSS compliant payments processor. **Appcues is not intended for the handling of end-user payment information.**

‍

#### Encryption

Appcues is committed to the privacy of information as it passes over the network, as well as to preventing unauthorized access to customer or end-user data. We use industry-leading encryption to protect all external traffic in transit (via [HTTPS/TLS](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security)) and at rest (using [AES-256](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Encryption_Standard) and an automated key rotation system).

‍

#### Data Retention

End-user and customer data in the Appcues platform is retained indefinitely by default. In the case that customers or individuals request the deletion of their data, Appcues will perform this deletion within seven working days.

Requests for data deletion may be addressed to [support@appcues.com](mailto:support@appcues.com).

### Legal

‍

#### GDPR and Privacy Shield

Part of Appcues' GDPR compliance strategy is adherence to the [EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks](https://privacyshield.gov/) as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Appcues has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://privacyshield.gov/>.

 **For any GDPR or Privacy Shield-related inquiries, please contact**[ **gdpr@appcues.com**](mailto:gdpr@appcues.com) **.**

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Appcues commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield compliance should first contact Appcues.  Appcues has further committed to cooperate with the EU and Swiss data protection authorities (DPAs) and comply with any advice given by the DPAs pertaining to compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, including remedial and compensatory measures for non-compliance.   Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website (<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>), individuals may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

Appcues is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission with regards to GDPR-related and other matters.

‍

#### Law Enforcement

Appcues will comply with any lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

‍

#### Transfer of Ownership

If Appcues merges with or is acquired by another company, the protections in this privacy policy may be subject to change.

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order and to provide fantastic customer service during the term of your service. We do not share this information with outside parties without your permission.

Although Appcues owns the data storage, databases and the Appcues site, you retain all rights to your content. We will also not utilize your content in our databases to compete with you, to advertise or market to your clients, or to contact your clients for any other means of profit.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses, except under the following circumstances:

  * If it becomes necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.
  * If Appcues is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, Appcues will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

‍

#### End User Customer Data

Appcues will collect End User Customer Data necessary to provide the service to you. “End User Customer Data” means information about your customers, which includes any information you elect to send to Appcues in your implementation as well as general information including but not limited to browser and device information.

We do not sell, share or disclose _any_ End User Customer Data with any third party, except if Appcues is acquired by or merged with another company.

### Questions?

‍

Please don't hesitate to [contact us at support@appcues.com](mailto:support@appcues.com).
